<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Carbonaut Documentation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Carbonaut Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>With ToC</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/table-of-contents/with-toc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/table-of-contents/with-toc/</guid><description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.
Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/architecture/</guid><description>To get an overview of the resource consumption of a cloud native system, you need to combine different data sources with each other. Carbonaut should be the platform to facilitate the data integration and transformation. To explore the architecture of the carbonaut system we first start with the data sources.
Data Sources # These data sources can be integrated dynamically (we add a data stream to the system) or static as (we use a configuration file to select a formular).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/architecture_old/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/architecture_old/</guid><description>This page describes the architecture of the Carbonaut project. This document is intended to convey the essence of the architecture, with further details available on separate concept sub-pages. The diagram below shows the general overview of the Carbonaut project, by describing each individual components in the following sections.
Context # The Carbonaut project aims to establish a data layer for environmental sustainability related software data so that it can be used by a variety of applications.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/connector-pugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/connector-pugins/</guid><description>Connector Plugins # &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/data-mixer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/data-mixer/</guid><description>Data Mixer # &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/data-schema/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/data-schema/</guid><description>Data Schema # &amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>